Contact

877/540-1020 (Work) shelia@hcmincorp.com

www.linkedin.com/in/shelia-n-hayden-wilson-3209534 (LinkedIn) www.hcmincorp.com (Company)

Top Skills

Treatment
Insurance
Case Managment

Certifications

Certified in Concealed Deadly Weapons

Certified Nurse Life Care Planner

Certified Scuba Diver

TN - Qualified Case Manager

NCIC - Qualified Rehabilitation Coordinator

Shelia N Hayden-Wilson

RN, CNLCP, CRRN, CCM, CCRN, SDAD, AMRE, RP Benton, Kentucky

Summary

Ambitious leader of a tenacious team of competent case managers in the workers compensation arena. A result of the aforementioned has rendered successful achievements of various National Certifications with our team. From inception, we have led individuals with high service standards, consistently demonstrating ability to provide outstanding, cost effective, comprehensive case management service by implementing Best Practices. HCMI's foundation and hallmark are based on quality. The case management of an injured client requires professional specialization and commitment. It requires working closely with the client, physician, employer, attorney, referral source, and other significant parties for the purpose of coordinating all aspects of case management. Knowledge of community resources, good counseling techniques, a commitment to quality, and succinct, timely case reporting are essential components in assisting the disabled client to attain his optimal level of functioning.

Experience

Heartland Care Management INC 14 years 9 months

President and Chief Operating Officer August 2010 - Present (9 years 11 months) Benton KY

HCMI is a full service case management and cost containment company. It was founded in 2005 under the name Heartland Care Management, Inc. as a private rehabilitation firm offering quality and timely service to disabled individuals. HCMI's commitment to excellence and to customer satisfaction has promoted consistent quality and steady growth. Sensitive to the needs of both our clients and our customers, HCMI has developed a wide range of services that provide access for each of our disabled or ill clients to quality,

cost effective medical care and vocational guidance, this offering them the chance to move on in life with dignity and integrity.

Director of Field Case Management / Utilization Review October 2005 - August 2010 (4 years 11 months)
Benton KY 42025

Heartland Care Management Inc. 2005-Present: Developed the infrastructure of the company and retain an active role as the HR Manager delivering Field Nurse Case Management and Utilization Reviews for Precertification purposes. Catastrophic Case Manager, Life Care Plans/Medical Cost Projections. We cover Kentucky, Tennessee, Southern Indiana, Southern Ohio, Southeast Missouri, North - South Carolina and Southern Illinois providing cost effective proactive field - catastrophic case management. HCMI hire/train qualified and diversified FCM's to provide a proactive service with the goal of return to successful and gainful employment in a proactive mindset.

Concentra Managed Care Services, Inc Certified Life Care Planner and Catastrophic Case Manager January 2000 - September 2005 (5 years 9 months) Kentucky

Certified Life Care Planner and Catastrophic Case Manager developing Life Care Plans and Medical Cost Projections and comprehensive catastrophic reports. Life Care Plans/Medical Cost Projections have been developed on diagnoses of RSD, Lymes Disease, amputations, paraplegia, closed head injuries, and aggressive pain management intervention (spinal cord stimulator and/or intrathecal therapy).

Concentra Managed Care Services, Inc. AKA Concentra Integrated Services, Inc
Senior Case Manager
January 1995 - January 2000 (5 years 1 month)
Kentucky

Senior Case Manager with relief supervision duties in absence of manager coupled with caseload of 35-40 files. Providing on-site case management of catastrophic injuries including traumatic brain injury, spinal cord injury, amputations, multiple trauma, chronic back pain, cancer, burns, HIV, & complicated fractures.

Concentra Managed Care Services, Inc. AKA Concentra Integrated Services, Inc.

Field Case Manager

January 1990 - January 1995 (5 years 1 month) Kentucky

Field Case Manager responsible for medical/vocational management of approximately 35 files. Position includes assessment of medical treatment, planning/implementation of appropriate interventions, assessing the effectiveness of care and treatment while defining ultimate goal of return to pre-injury lifestyle.

Lourdes Hospital

7 years

Intensive Care Unit - Critical Care Nurse 1987 - 1990 (3 years)

Paducah KY

Oncology Unit - Chemotherapy Charge Nurse 1985 - 1987 (2 years) Paducah Ky

Surgical Unit - State Registered Certified Nurse Aide 1983 - 1985 (2 years)

Paducah KY

Garrett's Farming Operation Co Owner 1972 - 1988 (16 years) Kentucky

Operation and management of family farm 3000 acres of row crop, 10 acres of tobacco, 7000-14000 hills vegetables for purpose of sales and 5 acres of bluegrass sod.

Garrett's Racing Arabians Co Owner 1978 - 1985 (7 years) Kentucky

Lourdes Hospital
Purchasing Unit - Purchasing Clerk
1972 - 1978 (6 years)
Paducah KY

Walgreens Deli

Waitress 1968 - 1973 (5 years) Paducah KY

Education

University of Kentucky
NURSING * Workers Compensation Medical Management, RN, CNLCP,
CRRN, CCRN, SDAD, AMRE, CCM, RP · (1978 - 1985)